A Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Coles Langhorne, 1974-1987
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Elizabeth Coles Langhorne, 1974-1987
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7942-c-d
This collection consists of 62 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on June 3, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist chiefly of drafts, galley and page proofs for "Monticello, a family story"; research material, drafts and page proofs for "Vieques: the history of a small island"; drafts, page and galley proofs and illustrations for "A Virginia family and its plantation houses"; and research notebooks for "Nancy Astor and her friends"; together with a catalog "The golden age of Albemarle, a portrait show 1800- 1860," a pamphlet, "Prestwould," and an article "Sanctuary-requiem."
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - "The Golden Age of Albemarle A Portrait Show 1800-1860" 1984, Printed (Box 1)
  - Monticello, A Family Story [ca. 1987], TMs, 2 folders (Box 1)
    An Early Draft
  - Monticello, A Family Story [ca. 1987], TMs (EC), 4 folders (Box 1)
    With corrections, two copies
  - Monticello, A Family Story 1987, TMs, 2 folders (Box 2)
    For the Recording for the Blind, Inc.
  - Monticello, A Family Story 1987, Galley proof, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Monticello, A Family Story 1987, Page Proofs (EC), 2 folders (Box 2)
    Two copies
  - Monticello, A Family Story 1987, Gathering (Box 3)
  - "Prestwould" 1982, Printed (Box 2)
  - "Sanctuary-Requiem" 1976, Printed (Box 3)
    in The Blue Guitar
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island n.d., TMs (Box 3)
    Research Material
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island [ca. 1987], TMs (Box 3)
    With corrections
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island [ca. 1987], TMs (EC); 2 folders (Box 3)
    Two Copies
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island [ca. 1987], TMs (Box 3)
    Incomplete Manuscript
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island 1987, Page Proofs (Box 4)
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island 1987, Page Proofs (EC) (Box 4)
  - Vieques: The History of a Small Island 1987, Paste-up Dummy (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses [1986], TMs (EC) (Box 4)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses [ca. 1986], TMs (Box 4)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, TMs & Page Proof (Box 4)
    Index
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, TMs (Setting Copy); 2 folders (Box 5)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Drawings (EC) (Box 5)
    Architectural Drawings
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Illustrations (EC) (Box 5)
    Illustrations
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Bound Copy (Box 5)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Galley Proofs (Box 5)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Galley Proofs (EC) (Box 5)
    Marked Set
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Galley Proofs (Box 5)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Page Proofs (Box 6)
    With Instructions to the Printer
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Page Proofs (EC); 2 folders (Box 6)
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Page Proofs (EC) (Box 6)
    Incomplete set
  - A Virginia Family and Its Plantation Houses 1987, Paste-up Dummy (Oversize N-10)
- Notebooks
  - Research Notebooks [ante 1974], 16 volumes (Box 7)
    re Nancy Astor and Her Friends
  - Research Notebooks [ante 1974], 16 volumes (Box 8)